So today is the first festival day of the Dark Malta festival. I've been here a few
days already and we've been out exploring we've been to Valletta to the
former capital of Malta to Medina we had a stroll around here in Slejema where we
staying and I'm so looking forward to visit some awesome yeah concerts today
tomorrow and the day after that so I'm going to get changed and then we'll head
to the bus
It just opened!
So this is... how should I call you?
This is my best friend.
She's here with me, Malta.
Introduce yourself.
Hello!
Second festival day and I decided on a PVC catsuit for today's outfit.
I think I'm going to be slightly overdressed.
Yesterday was fun but it was also pretty cold so I hope this is going to keep me warm today.
And yeah, the theme today is gold and black and I'm looking forward to see some cool bands.
We're going to the location a bit later than yesterday, so I had a pretty relaxed day so far.
And I'm going to check if Plüschi is ready.
Hi! Oh my gosh!
Then get ready, because we wanna go!
and the lady from Ashcode.
And I saw your concert yesterday,
it was awesome, really nice.
Thank you.
But you're also the faces behind Gothic Cat, I heard.
Mainly him.
Mainly you.
How did you come up with this idea
to use like album and band titles and cats?
We love ballets and we started with only two, three logos.
And at festivals six years ago,
And the people really like it.
The people love caps and music.
More than normal logos.
So, all started by chance.
Since I'm a fashion YouTube channel, where are your outfits from?
AliExpress.
Wish.
It's an Italian brand called Piazza Italia.
Okay, an Italian brand.
How did you like the Dark Monster Festival so far?
So far.
Yeah.
Yeah?
First time here.
Nice place, nice audience, and the performance yesterday was very good.
It was really good.
Very nice place.
Nice weather.
Nice weather, yeah.
So what do you think of my outfit?
Cool.
Really cool.
I like it.
Thank you guys.
Bye bye.
Bye.
I'm not a man, but it's my life
This is not what I want, and you're right
But could you stand down and tithe?
And what I said got you by the day
I'm alright, well, this isn't all bad
But it's my life
Thank you.
Alright, so it's day 3 of the Dark Mata Festival, the last day.
To be honest I'm a bit tired, but there are some cool bands today again, so we'll head
there in a few minutes. We've been to the pool today already and had a nice lunch and
day drinking. So Plüschi is already here and yeah I guess we'll drink our drinks and
then leave.
I don't even know your name
But this is just one thing that I do
I wanna see you
Die
So I'm here with Alera and DJ Hardest, Ike Aruni, they're the organizers of the Dark Malta Festival.
How on earth did you come up with the idea to do a gothic festival on Malta?
Well, me and a friend of mine, we opened a metal and gothic club in Zabud, which was the only club which catered for live metal bands in Malta.
And once we were at home and Aleira told me, listen, you always had this dream of kind of organizing this festival in Malta.
Why don't you organize this world of, now you have a venue.
Yeah.
But you can't do it.
Exactly.
And that's how it really ended.
That's how it started, maybe.
What has been your highlight so far this year?
I mean, I think the lineup itself is already a big highlight.
Yeah, it's great.
The biggest highlight.
The biggest lineup we ever had.
for next year where they have some very big bands confirmed.
So there's going to be a Dark Mata next year?
Yes, definitely yes.
There's already a lineup planned.
Oh nice.
How do you get the bands to play here in Malta?
Because really it's a big lineup.
It's a great lineup.
And such a small venue on a small island.
So how is it working?
Well, I think 50% maybe craziness.
Craziness?
That's for sure.
In fact, we have to thank all the bands for supporting us.
I'm waiting for the confirmation until the very last minute because there are so
over 100 flights involved. They think maybe lots of people don't think that bands to travel to Malta, they don't go on tour buses.
They have to come with a plane.
More difficult basically.
Okay, thanks so much. Thanks for coming here. Take care and have a great time.
Thank you. Thanks a lot. See you again next year. Yes.
The festival was a blast. I'm just not used to partying three days in a row and
being on a festival after like two years of no festivals and I look a bit
destroyed, hence the sunglasses. It was like a family meeting on the third day
because you came in, you checked everyone, said hi, you met the days before. It
It wasn't a really big festival but it was super well organized and just to stay here
at this isle and do some bit of vacation and go to the festival, have awesome party time,
is just something I can really recommend.
So I'm going to check if I can be back next year because it was really awesome.
I also got a t-shirt.
Everyone was dancing all the time, everyone was partying, having a good time.
It was just so cool to be back at concerts.
So actually we wanted to go on a boat trip today,
but we're not going to do that.
We slept in and a bit of hangover.
We're going to go out again and enjoy the sun
and have an awesome time for the last one and a half days.
We'll be right back.
We'll see you next time.